# MICHAEL KONIG

7101 Goodwin Road, Everson, WA 98247 · 707-235-2511

michael.konig@konigconcepts.com · www.linkedin.com/in/michaelkonigmk · konigconcepts.com

I am an automotive professional with a focus on project management, innovative engineering solutions, and evaluating ways to bring the next generation of driving experience to the industry. As the world moves to being more technology reliant, I would like to work with a strong team to bridge the gap between traditional automotive passion and new technical knowledge. I have a willingness to relocate for the right opportunity.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**JANUARY 2016 - JUNE 2018** 

## PROJECT MANAGER, WWU RACING, FORMULA SAE TEAM

Managed a team of 45 students to build a Formula SAE race car in one year. Built a start-up business model that replicates the industry. Established goals for the year and guided the team along a path to reach those goals. Raised, managed, spent, and reconciled a \$25,000 budget. Helped each team member develop into creative, detail oriented, analytical, and prepared engineers to function as a strong, cohesive team.

**JANUARY 2006 – OCTOBER 2011** 

### **DRIVING INSTRUCTOR/GUEST RELATIONS, WORLD CLASS DRVING**

Responsible for maximizing high-end clients' experiences. Instructed clients on driving a fleet of exotic cars. Marketed events and tours. Handled cross country travel and catering logistics. Maintained exotic fleet.

**FEBRUARY 2003 – AUGUST 2013** 

# FRONT OF THE HOUSE MANAGER, IL POSTO TRATTORIA / FUME BISTRO & BAR

Hired, trained, and managed 10 to 15 employees in two full service, up-scale restaurants. Assisted in developing menus, staff, interior design, policies, and marketing. Handled finances and HR on a daily basis.

## **EDUCATION**

**GRADUATION DATE: JUNE 2018 (EXPECTED)** 

# INDUSTRIAL TECHNOLOGY-VEHICLE DESIGN, BS, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

Lab based major with critical aspects of mechanical engineering, vehicle design, hands-on manufacturing, composites, CAD modeling, vehicle dynamics, and project management. Recipient of the Don Moon Scholarship, the Schaad Scholarship, and the Western Grant. **Expected graduating GPA: 3.33** 

**COMPLETION DATE: MAY 2005** 

## **MECHANIC/DRIVING TRAINING PROGRAM, JIM RUSSELL RACING SCHOOL**

Hands-on racing mechanic training program. Learned ground-up builds of open wheel race cars, vehicle dynamics, repairs, composite training, maintenance of a fleet of high performance cars for Audi, and motorsports business management. Attended composites classes at Abaris Training. Year-long driving school in parallel to the mechanic program with some of the top instructors in the world. Heavily involved in the building/prepping of the fleet of Formula 3 cars currently used at Simraceway Driving School.

### **SKILLS**

- Large scale project management
- Time management/task prioritization
- Commitment and a strong desire to get the job done
- Proficient with current technology trends and processes
- Motivating teams to work together towards a common goal
- Building plans, timelines, keep documentation
- Steady and focused in high pressure situations
- Ability to work dynamically

<sup>\*</sup>Portfolio and a more detailed resume available on website or LinkedIn listed above